《终空》前情提要
Previously on "Final Space"...
盖瑞和奎恩共赴第一次约会
Gary and Quinn go on their first date
与此同时  地球正被缺口吸走  狗带啦！
while the Earth is being sucked up into the breach. Holy crap!
盖瑞找到了反物质炸弹
Gary finds the anti-matter bomb,
不过要想引爆它  他们必须先过了
But to detonate it, they're gonna have to get past
总司令的火炉舰队关
the Lord Commander's fleet of incinerators.
他们能拯救世界吗？
Can they save the world?
准备好收看《终空》本季最后一集史诗巨制吧！
Get ready for the epic season finale of "Final Space"!
这些蠢蛋真的以为
Do these fools really think
我会让他们合上缺口吗？
that I'll allow them to close the breach?
我是被泰坦选中的人
I was chosen by Titans.
我们可能过不了这一关了
We might not make it out of this.
我只是想说... 我不知道我们是什么
I wanted to say... I don't know what we are.
一队船员？感觉我们的关系比这个更复杂
A crew? Feels like we're more than that.
或许是朋友？但对我来说
I mean, friends maybe? But to me,
我们更像是一个亲密  却又古怪的家庭
we've become like a close, but very strange family.
如果没有你们...
And without you...
- 我就不再是我了   - 我们！我们！
- I wouldn't be me. - Us! Us! Us! Us!
- 我们！   - 闭嘴  KVN！
- Uuuuus! - Shut the hell up, KVN!
我不会离开你的  盖瑞
I will never leave you, Gary.
我会做你永远的深空防精神错乱伴侣
I will be your deep space insanity avoidance forever companion.
我发誓  KVN！
I swear to God, KVN!
无论如何  不管发生什么  不管我们去哪
Anyways, whatever happens, wherever we go,
等这一切结束  我们一定要找到彼此
we find each other when this is over.
就这样定了？
Deal?
鸭嘴兽字幕组出品
翻译 + 专访听译 + 校对 + 压制：Kyl
Final Space - Chapter Ten
终空  第一季第十集
Sync & Correction by f1nc0 from Addic7ed.com
本字幕仅供学习交流  请于下载后24小时内删除
太多战舰了  盖瑞
There are too many, Gary.
我们不可能突围的
We'll never be able to break through.
HUE  你难道不能找一条路吗？
H.U.E., can't you find a way?
我们可以制造四级粒子灼烧
We can create a Level 4 Particle Burn.
好极了  不过鉴于我早就摆脱了化学试验材料包
Great. While I bust out my chemistry set,
能不能给我解释一下你说的是啥？！
how about explaining what the hell that means?!
意思就是  我们把光折核心发射出去  然后引爆它
It means we eject our lightfold core and detonate it.
什么？！
What?!
你的好主意就是把光折引擎给炸了？！
Your great idea is to explode our lightfold engine?!
Ooo-whoa.
HUE  准备发...
H.U.E., eject the ...
已发射  盖瑞
Done, Gary.
真的假的？
Seriously?
下次你能不能先警告我一下？
I mean, next time, can you warn me first?
盖瑞... 不会再有“下次”了
Gary... there is no "next time."
准备引爆  三... 二...
Detonating in 3... 2...
那是什么？
What is that?
...起爆
...Boomtown.
HUE 全速飞向缺口
H.U.E., full speed toward the breach.
我们有那么大一个东西需要合上
We got a freakin' hole to close.
这有意思吗？
Is this fun?
当然了！当然有意思！
It is! It is fun!
放虫群
Release the hives.
粉碎他们！
Crush them!
护盾已开启  盖瑞
Shields up, Gary.
HUE  那他喵的是啥？
H.U.E., what the crap is that?
是总司令的虫群战舰  盖瑞
The Lord Commander's hive ships, Gary.
如果它们噬穿了护盾
If they eat through the shields,
我们就没有其它防护措施了
there will be nothing left to stop them.
护盾能撑多久？
How long will the shields hold?
当前护盾完整度79%  数字正在下滑
Shield Integrity is at 79% and dropping.
至少还是... 还是个B-呢！
That's like a ... That's like a B-minus!
B-对应百分制的80-82。
还有救！
We're still good!
当前数据为63%
Now at 63%.
狗带！这个  这个撑死了只有D了！
Oh, crap! That's, like, a D, at best!
D对应百分制的65-66。
KVN  如果你不去外面的炮塔
KVN, if you don't get on the outside turret,
我就会把你打到只剩一口气
I will beat you within one inch of your life.
伙计们  我是最可抛弃的船员！恭喜我了
Guys, I'm the most expendable! Congratulations to me.
月饼  你去干什么？
Mooncake, what are you doing?
Chookity pok.
好吧  不过你不是可抛弃的
All right. But you're not expendable.
盖瑞  虫群在护盾上制造了太多缺口
Gary, the hives have breached the shield.
KVN和月饼对付不了多久的
KVN and Mooncake won't be able to hold them off for long.
哦不！哦不！
Oh, no! Oh, no!
这不是作战  这是死亡判决
This isn't a fight. It's a death sentence.
鹰式机能击退虫群吗？
Can a Hawk punch through the hive?
如果冲力足够的话  可以
Provided there is sufficient force, yes.
那我们就把反物质炸弹装在鹰式机上  然后飞出去
Then we will load the anti-matter bomb onto a Hawk and use that.
但那些无人机看到鹰式机以后  会马上进攻的
But as soon as the drones see the Hawk, they'll destroy it.
除非我们派一个人飞在前面开路
Not if we send somebody out first to clear the way.
- 我来   - 这不是小孩能胜任的任务
- I'll do it. - This is no job for a kid.
我面前的不再是小孩了  我面前的  是一个男猫汉
I don't see a kid anymore. I see a Man-Cat.
- 奎恩  我做得来   - 那我们就派小卡多开路
- Quinn, I can do this. - We will go with Little Cato.
所以他不会像他的父亲一样死掉
So that he doesn't die like his father.
哦  太冷血了  抱歉
Whoops, that was insensitive. Sorry.
让我们为你骄傲
Make us proud.
HUE  给他一架鹰式机
H.U.E., get him a Hawk.
- 注意安全  男猫汉   - 别担心  我可以的
- Be careful out there, Man-Cat. - Don't worry. I got this.
我太可以了
I so got this.
我太太太可以了
I got this so good.
哦  我可以的  我要出发了
Oooh, I got it. I'm gonna get this...
好的  该走了
All right, it's ready to go.
好好想想  这是阻止地球被吸走的
To think, that's the only thing stopping the Earth
唯一武器  现在它就在我手里
from getting swallowed up. And it's all on me.
我还以为看上去会更酷的
I thought it would've looked much cooler.
我应该画点火苗之类的吗？我带了好多笔
Should I draw some flames on it? I brought various tubes of this.
住手！不要在上面画火苗好不好？！
No! How about you don't draw flames on the anti-matter bomb?!
为时已晚了吗？正是
Is it too late?  It is.
- 万一我做不到呢？   - 那就做到你的最好
- What if I can't do it? - Try your best.
万一我的最好都还不够好呢？
What if my best isn't good enough?
你的最好  对我来说已经足够好了
It's good enough for me.
我有没有让你感觉更好了？当然！
Have I made things better? I did!
该走了
It's go time.
- 你在干什么？   - 我在完成任务
- What are you doing? - Finishing the job.
不过我才是要把它带到缺口的人
Except I'm the one taking it to the breach.
- 这是我的任务   - 真不巧  但这是我的命运
- It's my mission. - Too bad. It's my destiny.
你为什么要和我争这个？
Why are you fighting me?
因为失去你  是我远远不能承受的事！
Because I can take anything, except losing you!
哦  天哪  为什么  奎恩？！为什么我们到了这一步？
Oh, God, why, Quinn?! Why are we in this situation?!
早在我发现引力干扰的时候
From the moment I discovered the gravitational disturbance,
我就知道  这是我的人生大事
I knew this was my life's work.
如果你真的喜欢我...
If you really have feelings for me...
- 让我把这件事完成吧   - 我现在完全不知所措了！
- let me see this through to the end. - I am genuinely perplexed here!
因为我... 我不想让你死啊
'Cause I'm ... I'm trying to stop you from dying.
求你了
Please.
那么  奎恩·厄尔冈
Then, Quinn Ergon,
我会用尽最后一口气  确保你凯旋
I will use every last breath to make sure you succeed.
这是个真实又纯粹的承诺
That's a real, raw promise.
- 哈！   - 嗯
- Hwa! - Mmm.
太他妈... 太他妈棒了！
Hell... Hell, yeah!
等你回来  我们再继续
More of that when you come back.
不要离我而去
Don't die on me.
真好玩  我还以为我会当那个英雄呢...
Funny, I thought I was gonna be the hero...
- 不过你才是那个英雄   - 不  我们两个都是英雄
- but it's you. - No, it's both of us.
我们一直都是英雄
Always has been.
给我开路  小子们！
Punch a hole for me, boys!
好了  伙计们  全军出击
Okay, guys, all together now.
- 谢了  小卡多   - 搞定它  奎恩
- Thanks, Little Cato. - Finish it, Quinn.
如果有更多外援就好了
If only there was more help to call on.
如果有反抗军就好了
If only there was a Resistance.
等等  真的有反抗军  我还是领袖呢
Wait, there is a Resistance, and I'm its leader.
反抗军？到了该反抗的时候了吗？到了！
Resistance? Is it time to resist? It is!
我是三烦·梅内德斯将军
This is General Tribore Menendez.
所有部队  去11区
All battalions to Sector 11. Reeeeorr!
Reeeeorr! Reeeeorr!
Reeeeorr!
虫群已渗透银河一号
The hives have infiltrated the Galaxy One.
嘿！滚出我的飞船！
Hey! Get off my ship!
啊啊啊！
Aaahhhh!
这就是死亡的滋味吗？
Is this what death feels like?
不差嘛  只是  好奇怪啊
Not bad. It's just weird.
正在接近
Closing in.
- 啊！这只有我一个人了吗？   - 不  三烦还在
- Ah! Am I alone here? - No. Tribore's here.
我还带来了几个特别的朋友
And I brought some special friends.
啊！
Ahh!
谢了  三烦  我正在接近缺口
Thanks, Tribore. I'm closing in on the breach.
不妙吧？这还用说吗！
Is this bad? It sure the hell is!
不  三烦  我曾爱过你
No, Tribore. I loved you.
现在谁来领导反抗军？
Who's leading the Resistance now?
我来  我们要做的第一件事就是... 复仇
I am. First order of business ... revenge.
发射！
Eject!
耶  一石二鸟！干得漂亮
Yes. Two at once! Nice shot.
去死吧！走你！走你！走你
Down you go! Gotcha! Gotcha! Gotcha.
哇！我真是太帅了
Wow! I'm impressed with myself.
Ooh.
- 嘿  盖瑞？   - 怎么了  KVN？
- Hey, Gary? - What is it, KVN?!
- 很好玩  对吧？   - 哦！KVN！
- It's been fun, right? - Oh! KVN!
我猜挺好玩的？嘿！我玩得很开心...
I guess? Hey! I had fun...
太他妈美了
It's so beautiful.
召回虫群  准备好次元分流器
Call back the hives and ready the dimension splitter.
Chookity!
Ooh...
月饼！不！
Mooncake! No!
啊！呃啊！
Ah! Uh!
Ohhh...
Chookity pok!
你越挣扎  束缚就越强
The more you resist, the stronger the trap becomes.
嘿  月饼...
Hey, Mooncake...
我们可有的玩呢
We're going to have a lot of fun.
正在接近缺口
Approaching breach.
胜败在此一举
Here goes everything.
呃！
Ugh!
啊！
Aaah!
呃...
Ugh...
啊！
Agh!
呃啊！
Ughh!
汇报一下当前状态
Status report.
盖瑞  银河一号沦陷了
Gary, we have lost the Galaxy One.
我们还有左边的脉冲引擎呢
We still have a left pulse engine.
那是右边的脉冲引擎
It is the right pulse engine,
而且  它不足以对付总司令了
and it is not enough to face the Lord Commander.
盖瑞  有一条你没考虑到的出路
Gary, there's one option you haven't considered.
你可以弃船
You can abandon ship.
我不会离开的  这次不会
I'm not running away. Not this time.
这个想法曾经还说得通  不过... 我已经不是那个人了
At one point, that made sense, but... I'm not that guy anymore.
我会给你一块饼干的
I'd give you a cookie.
不过我猜  你已经长到不喜欢吃饼干的年龄了
But I think you've outgrown that now.
什么？！不！给我块饼干！
What?! No! Give me a cookie!
我永远  永远不会抛弃饼干的！
I will never, ever outgrow a cookie!
很抱歉  盖瑞  但它们不见了  全都不见了
I'm sorry, Gary, but they're gone. All gone.
太糟了  HUE！
That sucks, H.U.E.!
的确太糟了  盖瑞
It... really does, Gary.
我们不能让那个人得胜
We can't let this guy win.
盖瑞  我见过这个表情  重新考虑  请一定重新考虑
Gary, I know that look. Reconsider. Please.
没门  我不会重新考虑的
No way, Jose. I won't reconsider.
盖瑞  你设置了一条直接冲撞
Gary, you have set a collision course directly for
总司令的重型火炉舰的航线
the Lord Commander's Heavy Incinerator.
这是唯一能让他放过奎恩的办法
It's the only the way to stop him from taking out Quinn.
我还得去救月饼
And I have to save Mooncake.
我非得给你开出一个清单吗？！
Do I really have to make a list for you right now?!
如果我们决定出去干了  就要干一场大的
If we're going out, we're going out big.
我同意  我们必须用尽全力
Agreed. We must do everything possible
毁灭那个混蛋
to destroy that dick loaf.
咱们现在登场吧  你看如何？
What do you say we make an entrance?
就用它了  右侧的脉冲引擎
Right pulse engine is a go.
什么？他想干什么？！
What? What is he trying to accomplish?!
他已经失去所有东西了
He's already lost everything.
迫近警告！迫近警告！
Proximity alert! Proximity alert!
开火！把那艘飞船打飞！
Fire! Rip that ship from space!
我希望杀死你的过程能持续整整一辈子
I wish killing you could last a lifetime.
- 你准备好了吗？   - 动手啊！
- Ready for your turn? - Get on with it!
啊！
Aaaah!
盖瑞  银河一号...
Gary, the Galaxy One...
已经彻底毁坏了...
is destroyed...
HUE  快！把你的人工智能系统转到我的头盔里
H.U.E., quick! Transfer your AI into my helmet.
不  不  不  HUE！HUE？！
No, no, no. H.U.E.! H.U.E.?!
HUE！
H.U.E.!
是  盖瑞  我在这
Yes, Gary. I'm here.
我的老天哪  永远不要离开我  HUE
Oh, my gosh. Don't ever leave me, H.U.E.
永远不会的  盖瑞
Wouldn't think of it, Gary.
Chookity!
终空次元分流器已装载完毕
Final Space Dimension Splitter has been armed.
距离启动还有15秒
15 seconds until activation.
- 月饼！   - 你在这啊...
- Mooncake! - Here he is...
那个著名的英雄！“那个盖瑞”！
the infamous hero! The Gary!
我就叫... 盖瑞！
Just... Gary!
是的... 就是“那个盖瑞”！
Yes ...  ... just The Gary.
快放了他！他没对你做过任何事！
Let him go! He's done nothing to you!
你来的正好  你会亲眼看到月饼...
You're just in time to see Mooncake...
...开启终空的大门
...open the doorway of Final Space.
再坚持一下  小家伙！
Hang tight, little buddy!
Chookity...
呃！
Ugh!
你还不明白吗？你身边再也没有其他人了
Can't you see? There is no one beside you.
阿瓦卡多  他儿子  你的船员？
Avocato, his son, your crew?
你挂念的所有人都已经不在了！
Everyone you've cared about is gone!
一切都是因为它！
All because of that!
现在  你也快死了  不过不是痛快的死亡
And now, your life ends. But nothing quick.
我希望你能体验到长久的痛苦  就像你让我体验的那样
I want you to experience the same pain you put me through.
缓慢的  剧痛的死亡
A slow, painful death.
你想不明白吧？
You don't get it, do you?
正义的一方会赢的！向来都是如此
The good guys win in the end! They always do.
不  这次不是了  “那个盖瑞”
No. Not this time, The Gary.
- 不要  杰克   - 你为什么这么叫我？
- Don't do this, Jack. - Why would you call me that?
- 说啊！   - 你曾经很喜欢墨西哥小卷饼
- Speak! - You used to like taquitos
很喜欢和我爸一起打发时间
and hanging out with my dad, man.
啊  约翰·古茨比德的儿子
Ahh. John Goodspeed's son.
不过... 这并没有改变什么
Well... that changes nothing!
- 你可以不这么做的  杰克   - 别再叫我这个了！
- You don't need to do this, Jack. - Stop calling me that!
那个人在我被选中的那天就死了
That person died the day I was chosen.
我能说句真话吗？你可能会生气
Can I be honest, with the likelihood of pissing you off a little bit?
不过我才不管你是不是天选之人
I don't think you were chosen.
你能获得这些力量... 完全是出于巧合
You getting these powers... was just a mistake.
巧合？！
Mistake?!
- 啊啊啊！   - 啊！
- Rraaaaahh! - Aaahh!
现在  让我们一起看看终空里面是什么样吧
Now, let's take a look at what's inside Final Space.
啊！
Aaah!
这一刻终于来了！好极了！
The time has come! Yes!
带上我！
Take me!
我已经准备好成为泰坦  统治所有次元了！
I'm ready to be a Titan and rule every dimension!
不！不！不——！
No! No! Nooo!
盖瑞？
Gary?
- 奎恩...   - 对不起
- Quinn... - I'm sorry.
- 对不起... 什么？   - 我没早点告诉你
- For... what? - Not telling you sooner.
你可以等回来的时候再告诉我
You can tell me when you come back.
- 盖瑞...   - 不  别...
- Gary... - No, don't...
- 别说了   - 我不会回去了
- Don't say it. - I'm not coming back.
奎恩
Quinn.
我们已经失去了地球  但我还能救你
We've lost the Earth, but I can still save you.
永别了  盖瑞
Goodbye, Gary.
我会想念你的
I'll miss you.
奎恩？！
Quinn?!
你在开玩笑吧
You have got to be kidding.
HUE  把她救回来啊  快啊
H.U.E., get her back. Co-Come on.
奎恩！HUE  救救她啊！
Quinn! H.U.E., get her back!
奎恩！
Quinn!
HUE  我有多大可能逃出这片混沌
H.U.E., what are my chances of getting out of this mess?
以你现在的状态
In your current state,
再过10分钟  你就会死了
you will pass the point of recovery in 10 minutes...
9分钟... 8分钟...
9 minutes... 8...
7分钟...
7...
看啊  是卡尔
Look, it's Carl.
6分钟
6...
不可能...
It can't be...
5分钟... 4分钟...
5... 4...
3分钟...
3...
2分钟... 还有1分钟  饼干就烤好了
2... The cookies will be done in one minute.
好极了  我真的好激动啊...
Oh, good. I'm extremely excited...
有饼干诶
for these cookies.
0分钟
Zero.
盖瑞  饼干烤好了
Gary, the cookies are done.
我会想念你的  朋友
I'll miss you, friend.
- 嗨  儿子   - 我的老天哪
- Hey, son. - Holy crap.
我在做梦吗？
Am I dreaming?
- 没有   - 哦  那... 我已经...
- No. - Oh. Well. Then... I'm...
- 是的   - 成吧  这可不太好
- Yep. - Well, crap, that's not good.
我其实... 我其实希望你会说“没有”呢
You see, I was ... I was hoping for a no.
我被派来  是为了给你一个选择
I was sent to give you a choice ...
你可以跟我走  或者一个人回去
to come with me or to go back.
那边... 有什么？
What's... that way?
很多  非常非常多的进口啤酒
Lots, and I mean lots, of imported beer.
- 难以置信的数量   - 到底有多少啤酒？
- It's actually ridiculous. - How much beer are we talking?
特别多
Too much.
那边呢？
And back that way?
一条被死亡和心碎充满的危机之路
A perilous journey full of death and heartbreak.
小卡多在哪条路上？
Which way is Little Cato?
月饼在哪条路上？
Which way is Mooncake?
奎恩在哪条路上？
Which way is Quinn?
Sync & Correction by f1nc0 from Addic7ed.com
幕后专访
INSIDE THE EPISODE
呃... 杀死KVN实在太爽了
Yeah... Killing KVN was great
我不是讨厌他  我其实很喜欢这个角色
Not I hate this guy. I love the character.
而且我真心认为  这部剧最搞笑的镜头之一
And I think, honestly, it's probably one of the funniest moments of the show,
就是KVN被毁掉以后
is when you see KVN destroyed,
盖瑞走到窗边  看到KVN的尸体
Gary walks up to the window, he sees KVN's lifeless body
你还以为盖瑞会感到很难过来着
and then you expect him to be like, OK, this is the moment when Gary's gonna feel real bad
这是我写得最爽的镜头之一
One of my favorite moments to write.
我们在每集开始都放置了倒计时
We did this flash forward at the beginning of every episode,
让观众们去猜下一步会发生什么
leave audiences wondering like where's this going.
就是... 盖瑞越来越虚弱  他快要死了
This is like... Gary's like essentially getting worse and worse. He's dying.
观众们看着时间一分一秒流逝  最终以此收场
They're watching every minute tick by, and finally snaps to it
很棒的场景
Such a cool moment.
因为你会想  这就是我在看的东西！
Cause you're like, this is what's I've been seeing!
这就是我一直在看的东西！
This is what's I've been seeing the whole time!
原来结局是这样的！
It finally comes to this!
总司令还没死
Lord Commander isn't dying.
月饼还在他手里  他还有进入终空的可能
He still has Mooncake, and this guy can still get into Final Space.
尽管他失去了第一次机会
Even though he missed one opportunity,
不过我觉得还会有其它机会的
I think another opportunity is gonna show itself.
到时我们就知道了
We'll see.